FREELANCE WEBSITE DESIGNER

Summary

Marine Corps trained leader and business development specialist. With an extensive background in many facets throughout the operational side of a business, I always seek out ways to assist and improve my teams training and overall performance.

I have in 12+ years of experience in website development, internet research and seo, 4 years experience in purchasing, training, and supply chain control for the military, 15+ years in b2b/b2c sales, business loan brokering, and real estate investment training.

I bring with me an impeccable work ethic, thanks to my time in the Marines, to ensure an exemplary outcome to all goals that my position requires.

Experience

Rakuten Boston, MA Freelance Website Designer 09/2012 to Current

- Specialized in cold calls to business owners looking for a web designer or online marketing manager for their businesses online presence and marketing necessities.
- Focused on sales for websites, and website development, logo designs, and online marketing services/materials on a remote independent contractor for hire basis.
- Cross selling of widget applications and installation assistance for current and newly designed websites, with tracking links for lead development and follow up.
- Sales and creation of ads, back links, marketing promotions on sites such as Twitter, Facebook, and Foursquare, and consistently generating new ideas to ensure above average marketing results.
- Over 10 years experience with internet based web designing, marketing, SEO, PPC, social media networks, and analytic research, as well online presentations, web research, email response handling and customer support.

Pnc Financial Services Group, Inc. Portland, PA Account Manager 08/2013 to 05/2014

- Contacted Prime Military Defense Contractors, Contract Managers, Small Business Liaison Officers, Purchasing Managers, and Buyers on a daily basis.
- B2B development calls at an average of 150 outbound calls a day.
- Obtained Request for Quotes, Bids, and Information requirements for the procurement of capacitors, electronic components, semi conductors, hard to find parts, and commercial off the shelf items.
- Created and sent out mass marketing campaigns via email, social media, LinkedIn, and newsletter distribution.
- Developed ongoing business supplier relationships on a daily basis for the securing of future requirements.
- Signed the company up on a daily basis with 10 new supplier diversity portals for automated submissions and receipt of requirements.

NavMar Investments LLC City, STATE Owner / Senior Business Consultant 04/2006 to 09/2012

- Responsible for lead development through self generation of internet marketing campaigns, b2b cold calls, relationship development, live networking and referrals from sales.
- Reviewing of business credit standings and personal credit reports, as well as additional financial documents in order to properly obtain lines of credit for the businesses needs.
- Created professional relationships with lending institutions in order to accelerate the processing of the applications in a swift and efficient
- Utilized proper demographic research in order to establish a target market for the promotions that certain financial institutions we lending for.
- Established a working network of lenders and brokers for lending submission through internet applications.
- Follow up calls for renewing loans and cross selling of additional products for the continuing relationship with current and past business
 owners and clients.

Whitney Education Group City, STATE Senior Investment Advisor 11/2002 to 04/2007

- Called current client list daily for cross sale of additional education training programs and collecting on current program balances.
- Selling additional trainings for students looking to advance their education, Sales for my department (9 sales reps) reached over \$8.4 million in 2006
- Collection responsibilities for outstanding balances owed on unpaid tuition's, Collections for my department (9 reps) in 2006 reached over \$32 million.
- Traveled extensively to for presenting materials to students of higher level trainings in order to ensure up sells from current training and membership programs.
- Advising on all aspects of investment deals such as foreclosure, wholesale, lease options, owner financed, rentals, mobile homes, land development, for sale by owners, new construction, and rehabs.
- Fiscal Chief/NCOIC.

United States Marine Corps City, STATE NCOIC 01/1997 to 01/2001

- Training and development of future NCO's (Non Commissioned Officers) as well as assisting in the physical and professional trainings of all Marines within my unit.
- Negotiated prices, quantities, deliveries, and payments of merchandise from vendors on a worldwide scale.
- Prepared and presented daily, weekly, and monthly budgeting and accounting reports.
- Utilized various methods of payment for materials and services in order to accomplish tasks in a timely and cost effective manner.
- Resolved wide range of customer problems, applying diplomacy and assertiveness to fee and budget discrepancies.
- Management of SABRS (Standards Account Budgeting Reports System)
- Contract procurement of \$350k annually.
- Provided logistic support for the squadrons on an international level.
- Pricing and cost analysis in the purchasing for the military requirements and mission accomplishment based on approved budget restrictions.
- Responsible for inventory tracking and materials accountability using electronic spreadsheets (CMR Consolidated Memorandum Receipts.)

Education

Associate of Science 2001 United States Marine Corps , City , State High School Diploma 1993 Cypress Lake High School , City , State Achievements

Associates Degree with 2yrs credit towards Bachelors Degree

Honorable Discharge Certificate of Commendation (3) Good Conduct Medal (1) Letter of Recognition (2)

Meritorious Promotion (1) NCO of the Qtr for MAG 26. (1) Letter of Recommendation (1)

Skills

Accounting, bookkeeping, budget development, content development, customer service, database creation and maintenance, employee training, Microsoft Office, SalesForce, Zoho, Outlook, online networking.